Guide to the United States Mint errors and misprints (coins and paper), 1930-2012.
United States Mint errors and misprints (coins and paper)
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
United States Mint errors and misprints (coins and paper), 1930-2012.
8491
0.1 cubic feet.
Coins.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Coin and paper money US misprints.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Coin and paper money US misprints.
SUBJECTS
Names:
United States Mint.
Subjects:
Coins -- United States.; Paper money -- United States.
Form and Genre Terms:
Coins (money); Paper money.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Coins
Series II. Paper Money
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Coins
  - New Hampshire State Quarter, 2000; Rudin # E-2; Struck 15% off center Graded: SEGS graded Mint State 65 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Connecticut State Quarter, 1999; Rudin # E-3; Broadstruck Graded: Choice (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Georgia State Quarter, 1999; Rudin # E-3; Broadstruck Graded: Choice (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - New Jersey State Quarter, 1999; Rudin # E-4; Missing the clad layer on the back Graded: NGC Graded MS 63 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Lincoln Penny, 1999; Rudin # E-27; Broadstruck with Zinc profile (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Roosevelt Dime, 1991; Rudin # E-28; Struck 70%off center (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Washington quarter, 1985; Rudin # E-29; Struck50% off center (Box 1, Folder 5a)
  - Lincoln Penny, 2001; Rudin # E-30; Double Strike to both sides (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Lincoln Penny, 1964; Rudin # E-31; Struck 75% off center (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Kennedy Half Dollar, 1976; Rudin # E-32A; Struck 20% off center Graded: NGC MS 65 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Eisenhower Liberty Coin, 1974; Rudin # E-41; Face slightly off center (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Lincoln Penny, 1968S; Rudin # E-51; Penny on dime planchet Graded: PCGS MS 64 Mint (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Susan B. Anthony dollar, 1999; Rudin # E-54; Broadstruck south of center (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Massachusetts State Quarter, 2000; Rudin # E-55; Struck 25% off center, rims are missing, no reeding to edges (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Nickel, 1981; Rudin # E-57; Double strike. Second strike 100% off center (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Massachusetts State Quarter, Rudin # E-58; Struck 95% off center (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Washington Quarter, 1966; Rudin # E-59; Quarter struck on nickel planchet Graded: MGN AU 55 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Washington Quarter, 1997D; Rudin # E-60; Struck 10% off center on a triple clipped planchet Graded: NGC MS 64 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Indian Head Penny, 1889; Rudin # E-66; Second strike 90% off center Graded: PCGS (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Lincoln Penny, 1944; Rudin # E-67; Reverse Brockage Graded: ANACS AU 55 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Roosevelt Dime, 1965; Rudin # E-68; Struck 45% off center Graded: Fine (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Jefferson Nickel, 1978; Rudin # E-69; Struck on a penny planchet (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Lincoln Penny, 1955; Rudin # E-71; Double die Graded: NGC Graded AU 55 BN about uncirculated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Kennedy Half Dollar, 1964; Rudin # E-72; Accented hair Graded: PCGS PR 65 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Lincoln Penny, Rudin # E-73; Overstruck with full mirror brockage from reverse of dye, overstrike rotated 180 degrees from front strike Graded: PCGS MS 64 RD (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Lincoln Penny, 2001; Rudin # E-74; Double Struck, broadstruck and indented Graded: PCGS MS 63 RD (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Lincoln Penny, Rudin # E-76; Obverse struck through capped die Graded: NGC MS 63 RB (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Morgan dollar, 1900; Rudin # E-77; Top 100 double stars, VAM 15 Graded: PCGS MS 64 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Lincoln Penny, 1943S; Rudin # E-78; Struck on a ten cent planchet Graded: NGC graded VF (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Wisconsin Quarter, 2004D; Rudin # E-79; Extra leaf high Graded: NGC graded MS 66 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Nickel, Rudin # E-85; Double strike, one small one large Graded: Near fine (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Dime, 2000; Rudin # E-86; Double strike Graded: Near fine (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Washington Dollar, 2007; Rudin # E-95; Plain edge, all edge lettering is missing Graded: Brilliant UNC (Box 4)
  - Adams Dollar, 2007; Rudin # E-96; Plain edge, all edge letter is missing Graded: MS 65 (Box 4)
  - Two Adams Dollars, 2007; Rudin # E-97; One with inverted edge lettering, one with overlapped edge lettering (Box 4)
  - Van Buren Dollar, 2008; Rudin # E-98; Last "Godless" dollar error coin, missing edge lettering Graded: PCGS MS 65 (Box 4)
  - Four Presidential Dollars, 2009; Rudin # E-99; Four "In God We Trust" presidential dollars--Harrison, Tyler, Polk and Taylor--missing edge lettering Graded: Brilliant uncirculated (Box 4)
  - Sacagawea dollar, 2001; Rudin # E-100; Experimental rinse caused color change Graded: PCGS MS 66 (Box 4)
  - Sacagawea dollar, 2009; Rudin # E-101; First Sacagawea error coin, missing edge lettering Graded: PCGS MS 65 (Box 4)
  - Sacagawea dollar, 2010; Rudin # E-102; Second Sacagawea error coin, missing edge lettering Graded: PCGS MS 64 (Box 4)
  - Two Morgan Dollars, 1878; Rudin # E-103; Eight tail feather and seven tail feather varieties Graded: Circulated (Box 4)
  - One cent, five cent, ten cent, Rudin # E-104; Error coin folio, coins struck off-center Graded: Uncirculated (Box 4)
  - Illinois, Maine and Missouri State Quarters, 2003; Rudin # E-105; Mint cancelled errors Graded: Brilliant uncirculated (Box 4)
- Series II. Paper Money
  - $5.00, 1993; Rudin # E-1; Serial numbers and seals on the back Graded: Gem crisp (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - $100.00, 1990; Rudin # E-5; Insufficient ink on the back plus green ink line in right margin of the back Graded: Choice (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - $100.00, 1996; Rudin # E-6; Alignment error plus shift of the serial numbers most visibly on the left side Graded: Choice AU (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - $10.00, 1950A; Rudin # E-7; Gutter folds on face and back Graded: PCGS 45 PPQ extremely fine (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - $10.00, 1974; Rudin # E-8; Ink smears on the back Graded: PCGS 40 PPG extremely fine (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - $2.00, 2003; Rudin # E-9; Drawn on Notes is Sailor "Popeye" original sketch by Hy Eisman. (Box 2, Folder 13A)
  - $2.00, 1953; Rudin # E-10; Misaligned back printing (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - $5.00, 1963A; Rudin # E-11; Seals and serial numbers shifted to the right (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - $1.00, 1974; Rudin # E-12; Seals and serial numbers inverted (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - $1.00, 1977A; Rudin # E-13; Full back to face offset (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - $1.00, 2006; Rudin # E-14; Misplaced seal on left hand side (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - $1.00, 1957B; Rudin # E-15; Mismatched serial numbers Graded: PCGS 65 PPQ Gem (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - $10.00, pre-1963; Rudin # E-16; Missing both seals and serial numbers as well as the series and signature printings Graded: PCGS 64 PPQ very choice (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - $1.00, 1981; Rudin # E-17; Full face to back offset Graded: PCGS 63 PPQ choice (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - $1.00, 1995; Rudin # E-18; Missing back printing Graded: PCGS 58 PPQ choice (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - $20.00, 1974; Rudin # E-19; Printed foldover Graded: PCGS 63 PPQ choice (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - $1.00, 1977; Rudin # E-20; Missing seals and serial numbers on front (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - $20.00, 1990; Rudin # E-21; Magnetic ink skips (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - $1.00, 1935E; Rudin # E-22; Blank corner on upper left on the back (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - $2.00, 1976; Rudin # E-23; Seals and serial numbers shifted upwards (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - $1.00, 1969B; Rudin # E-24; Ink transfer error to front lower right (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - $5.00, 1985; Rudin # E-25; Insufficient ink to back (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - $1.00, 1995; Rudin # E-26; Missing serial numbers and one seal (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - $5.00, 1963A; Rudin # E-32; Green ink smear on back plus Bureau of Printing and Engraving red rejection mark on front Graded: PCGS 66 PPQ gem (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - $1.00, 1969B; Rudin # E-33; Ink transfer error to front lower right (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - $20.00, 1995; Rudin # E-34; Offset printing, two bills visible on face, seals and serial numbers are not centered (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - $1.00, 1935E; Rudin # E-35; Gutter fold to lower left corner (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - $50.00, 1977; Rudin # E-36; Partial face to back offset Graded: PCGS 58 PPQ choice (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - $20.00, 1985; Rudin # E-37; Too much ink on back (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - $10.00, 1950; Rudin # E-38; Pre-face print foldover, folded lower corner Graded: PCGS 35 PPQ very fine (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - $10.00, 1969; Rudin # E-39; Series 1969 B Full back to front wet ink transfer with inspector's red rejection mark on face (Box 2, Folder 37a)
  - $100.00, Rudin # E-40; Entire face is blank except for seals and serial numbers Graded: PMG 66 EPQ gem (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - $20.00, 1981; Rudin # E-42; Full face to back offset Graded: PMG 58 EPQ choice (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - $5.00, 1981; Rudin # E-43; Green ink smear on back (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - $5.00, 1981; Rudin # E-44; Green ink smear on back (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - $10.00, 1969; Rudin # E-45; Star note, green ink smear on back Graded: PCGS 66 PPQ gem (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - $10.00, 1974; Rudin # E-46; Serial numbers and seals are low, also shows Bureau's red rejection mark on face (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - $1.00, 1999; Rudin # E-47; Seal on left hand side is low Graded: (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - $1.00, 1957A; Rudin # E-48; Gutter fold down center on face (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - $1.00, 1935D; Rudin # E-49; Butterfly lower right hand side of face (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - $5.00, 1981; Rudin # E-50; Pre face print foldover (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - $100.00, 1999; Rudin # E-52; Missing seal Graded: PMG 58 EPQ (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - $1.00, Rudin # E-53; Missing right serial number, treasury seal, series year and treasury secretary signature (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - $1.00, Rudin # E-56; Insufficient ink on face Graded:PMG 55 EPQ (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - $5.00, 1928C; Rudin # E-61; Inverted back, plate letter C Graded: FR 1528 VF (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - $1.00, 1981; Rudin # E-62; Solvent smear on face Graded: PCGS 64 PPQ very choice new (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - $1.00, 1985; Rudin # E-63; End of roll error Graded: PCGS 63 PPQ Choice new (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - $1.00, 1988; Rudin # E-64; Overinked black overprint of district seal Graded: PCGS 40 PPQ extremely fine (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - $20.00, 1969C; Rudin # E-65; Partial offsets on face and back Graded: PCGS 58 PPQ choice about new (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - $10.00, 1988A; Rudin # E-75; Partial multiple back printing, ink on back soaked through from front Graded: PCGS FR 2028A choice about new 55 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - $1.00, 1977; Rudin # E-80; Seal and numbers on left side show dramatic shift downward Graded: PMG choice uncirculated 63 EPQ (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - $20.00, 1977; Rudin # E-81; Obstructed printing error caused by stray sheet, missing about 40% of face printing Graded: PMG choice about uncirculated 58 EPQ (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - $5.00, 1988A; Rudin # E-82; Back is perfectly centered while face is shifted about 1/2 inch Graded: PCGS choice about new 58 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - $100.00, 1977; Rudin # E-83; Full face to back offset printing Graded: PCGS extremely fine 45 PPQ FR 2168B (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - $20.00, 1996; Rudin # E-84; Partial face to back offset printing, large portrait Graded: PMG choice very fine 35 FR 2083 A (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - $1.00, 1935E; Rudin # E-87; Cutting error--3 items Graded: Uncirculated (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - $20.00, 1977; Rudin # E-88; Dramatic cutting error--3 items Graded: Uncirculated (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - $5.00, 1974; Rudin # E-89; Partial back to face offset printing Graded: PCGS very fine apparent FR 1973 L (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - $100.00, 1977; Rudin # E-90; Printed foldover, treasury seals and serial numbers (one only partial) appear on back. From the Arden collection Graded: PCGS choice about new 58 PPQ FR 2168 J (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - $10.00, 1950A; Rudin # E-91; Gutter fold error plus cutting error Graded: Almost uncirculated (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - $20.00, 1990; Rudin # E-92; Board break Graded: EF-AU (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - $10.00, 1950; Rudin # E-93; Double printed back Graded: Fine (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - $50.00, 1934C; Rudin # E-94; A piece of rag might have caused smear on face Graded: AU (Box 3, Folder 27)